<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CoderBot - An open, programmable robot</title>
    <description>CoderBot is an open source, raspberry pi robot specialized in teaching kids the basics of robotics and coding.
</description>
    <link>http://coderbot.org/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://coderbot.org/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 00:31:12 +0200</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Apr 2015 00:31:12 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Motor control board updated</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The new motor control board (or “hat”, in Raspberry PI terms) is finally here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The board enable the PI to control two motors, either DC via L293D or Servo, and two additional Servos which can be used for different purposes: a robotic crane, to rotate ant tilt the camera or new, yet to be conceived ideas that will be part of the next version of CoderBot, 2.0, currently under development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The board is compatible with Raspberry PI model A, B, B+ and the very new model B 2 (honestly, it was not yet tested on that one, but we look forward to play with it!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/coderbot_board_2_0_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;intro&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The design is available &lt;a href=&quot;http://123d.circuits.io/circuits/412909-coderbot-motor-shield-servo-dc-combo#pcb&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; as a gerber file. If you are interested in getting one copy, please &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#105;&amp;#110;&amp;#102;&amp;#111;&amp;#064;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#100;&amp;#101;&amp;#114;&amp;#098;&amp;#111;&amp;#116;&amp;#046;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#103;&quot;&gt;contact us&lt;/a&gt; for more info.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2015 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderbot.org/blog/2015/05/07/en-board-2-0.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderbot.org/blog/2015/05/07/en-board-2-0.html</guid>
        
        <category>news</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
      
    
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Hour of Code 2014 - Build and code your own robot!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Learning to code in order to be active and creative players in the digital revolution, this is the “motto” of the “Hour Of Code” initiative that let, for the second year, millions of kids experience computer programming in order to be a creative “producer”, rather than just a passive “consumer” in the digital revolution.
In Milano, Italy, thanks to the support of CoderDojo Milano, which organised a very special “digital creativity” workshop with several activities, a session dedicated to robots took place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/coderbot_hoc_2014_12_13_1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;intro&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The session, named “Build - and code - your own robot” was about assembling and programming a CoderBot and was attended by eight children (age 8-13).
Once assembled, the robot was programmed by kids to move and explore the place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/coderbot_hoc_2014_12_13_2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;desc&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The workshop was divided in three parts:
short introduction to robotics: what is a robot and how it is used
assembling the robot
programming the robot&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/coderbot_hoc_2014_12_13_3.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;middle&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the first part, which was held by mentors with a classical, “frontal lesson” approach, the kids, in couples, have assembled their own robot using the provided parts and using a pre-assembled robot as “model”.
Once assembled, the robots have been tested and a short description of the programming interface have been given to children, then they started to autonomously experiment the robot and develop programs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/blog/coderbot_hoc_2014_12_13_4.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;conclusion&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conclusions
Kids showed great interest in the initiative. Apart from the very positive feedback, it is worth noting that almost all of the attendants continued to work all the available time and did not even enjoy the usual mid session “cookie-break”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9rWKXD2UzS8&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://img.youtube.com/vi/9rWKXD2UzS8/0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;video&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 14 Dec 2014 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderbot.org/blog/2014/12/14/en-hour-of-code-2014.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderbot.org/blog/2014/12/14/en-hour-of-code-2014.html</guid>
        
        <category>doc</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
    
      
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to CoderBot all-new website</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;CoderBot finally gets a whole new website with all the information required to actually make the robot out of standard, generally available parts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/build_hw.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;make&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the CoderBot &lt;a href=&quot;/en/how_to_build_mh.html&quot;&gt;Mechanics&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;/en/how_to_build_hw.html&quot;&gt;Hardware&lt;/a&gt; documentation for mechanical and electronics assembly instructions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the CoderBot &lt;a href=&quot;/en/how_to_build_sw.html&quot;&gt;Software&lt;/a&gt; documentation for instructions on installing and configuring the software components.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many thanks to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.giuliaolivares.it/&quot;&gt;Giulia&lt;/a&gt; for the logo and graphics!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the following days, the &lt;a href=&quot;/en/projects.html&quot;&gt;Play and learn&lt;/a&gt; section will be enriched with detailed instructions and guides, as well as games and projects tailored for the robot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope this website will foster CoderBot project development and improvement, and that the project itself will become a useful and fun tool for learning.
In order to collect questions, issues and suggestions a &lt;a href=&quot;https://groups.google.com/forum/#!forum/coderbot-users&quot;&gt;dedicated forum&lt;/a&gt; is now open, please use it as to communicate about the project.
To get updates on the project, subscribe to the &lt;a href=&quot;/en/contact.html&quot;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt; and follow it on the &lt;a href=&quot;/en/contact.html&quot;&gt;social media&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
        <link>http://coderbot.org/blog/2014/10/01/en-coderbot-nuovo-sito.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://coderbot.org/blog/2014/10/01/en-coderbot-nuovo-sito.html</guid>
        
        <category>doc</category>
        
        <category>announce</category>
        
        
        <category>blog</category>
        
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>
